<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Adrian Marcu</title>
        <link>https://adrian-marcu.com/</link>
        <description>Adrian Marcu Senior Software Engineer Freelancer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:11:21 &#43;0300</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://adrian-marcu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>🚀 My Journey into Building a SaaS Product: A Wild Ride</title>
    <link>https://adrian-marcu.com/my-journey-into-building-a-saas-product-part-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:11:21 &#43;0300</pubDate>
    <author>Adrian Marcu</author>
    <guid>https://adrian-marcu.com/my-journey-into-building-a-saas-product-part-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I took a leap into the crazy world of building SaaS products, and I have to say—it’s been a wild ride. Along the way, I’ve learned a lot about the tech stacks popular among startups, and I wanted to share my thoughts and experiences.
Starting the Startup Journey So, what do you do when you have a solid technical background, gained from working in big companies, and decide to start your own startup?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Redefining Development: The Future of AI in the Hands of Developers</title>
    <link>https://adrian-marcu.com/redefining-development/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 17:11:21 &#43;0300</pubDate>
    <author>Adrian Marcu</author>
    <guid>https://adrian-marcu.com/redefining-development/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence (AI) is becoming a more significant component of software development as technology progresses. Developers who adopt AI technology will have a significant competitive advantage in the years to come as it has the potential to revolutionize the way we design, build, and maintain software. This article will examine the potential applications of AI in software development for both developers and businesses.
AI and Software Design Software design is one of the most important aspects of software development, and AI has the potential to revolutionize the way we approach it.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Another perspective on microservices architecture</title>
    <link>https://adrian-marcu.com/another-perspective-on-microservices/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:42:45 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Adrian Marcu</author>
    <guid>https://adrian-marcu.com/another-perspective-on-microservices/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A well-liked software design pattern that enables the creation and deployment of independently scalable and maintainable services is the microservices architecture. One of the key benefits of this architecture is its resiliency - the ability to withstand failures and continue functioning without interruption.
There are many in which microservices architecture can improve resiliency and help ensure that your applications remain available and responsive in the face of unexpected events. My personal experience has shown that microservices primarily brought four benefits:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Pitfalls when overdesigning a system</title>
    <link>https://adrian-marcu.com/system-overdesign/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 14:16:53 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Adrian Marcu</author>
    <guid>https://adrian-marcu.com/system-overdesign/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[From experience I can tell you that I&rsquo;ve seen this pattern many times. I was getting too excited when starting a new project and I would think of alot of side features rather than doing the minimum viable solution. It&rsquo;s almost like when you get distracted doing all the side quests first in a video game and in the end you can&rsquo;t find the motivation to do the very thing that got you interested in the first place.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Freelancing Isn&#39;t as Scary as you Think</title>
    <link>https://adrian-marcu.com/freelancing/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 19:18:16 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Adrian Marcu</author>
    <guid>https://adrian-marcu.com/freelancing/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Are you a software developer considering freelancing or an established freelancer trying to maintain your position in the market?
Whatever your circumstance, it can be challenging to keep up with the most recent trends and best practices in the world of freelancing as a software developer because it is continuously changing. We&rsquo;ll look at some of the crucial factors for becoming and continuing to be a successful freelance software developer in my first blog post.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
